svsu.edu 2019-12-24

# Privacy Statement - Saginaw Valley State University

## Privacy Statement for Saginaw Valley State University

This online privacy statement is intended to inform you of the ways in which this website (“Site”) collects information, the uses to which that information will be put, and the ways in which we protect the information you choose to provide us.

Please note that other Saginaw Valley State University websites may adopt different privacy practices as their specific needs require. 

Use of this Site is subject to all applicable state and federal laws, as well as general University policies.

## **Information Collected**

This Site collects two general types of information: (a) information you voluntarily provide to us, which may include personal information (such as your name, address, e-mail address, etc.), and (b) information we collect automatically when you visit this Site through cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs. 

### **Information Voluntarily Provided by You**

This Site will only collect personal information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide by, for example, responding to surveys, completing inquiry forms, sending e-mails, etc.  It is this Site’s general practice to use personal information only for the purposes for which it was requested and any additional uses specifically stated on the Site.  However, information collected through this Site may be subject to the University’s obligation to respond to subpoenas, court orders, discovery requests, and requests for public records under the Michigan Freedom of Information Act.  Further, the disclosure of information collected through this Site is subject to the provisions of the Family Educational Rights & Privacy Act.   

The University may also access or permit access to information collected through this Site in accordance with and subject to the limitations of the University’s [Internet and Network Resources Acceptable Use Policy](http://svsu.edu/operationsmanual/generaloperations/generaloperationsii/461internetandnetworkresourcesacceptableus/)

**Security of your Personal Information**

Although this Site has security measures in place to protect personal information provided to us by users, users should also take steps to protect personal information by, for example, closing all web browsers after using the Site.  Information disclosed in chat rooms, news groups, forums, message boards and similar contexts may become public.  Users should, therefore, exercise caution before disclosing personal information in such contexts.

When you engage in financial transactions at our Site, you may be asked for a credit card number.  Unless otherwise noted on the Site, credit card transactions are encrypted and the server that processes your credit card information is secure.  Such information may also be saved in an encrypted format or in internal systems that are protected by a firewall system. This Site complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard.

**Updating Personal Information**

You may correct, update, or remove the personal information provided to us through the use of the Site. In particular: 

  * **Student and alumni contact information listed in the Directory Lookup** \- to change personal information in the student and alumni people directory, visit <https://webtech.svsu.edu/lookup/>
  * **Faculty, staff, and retiree contact information listed in the Directory Lookup** – to change personal information in the faculty, staff and retiree people directory, visit <https://webtech.svsu.edu/lookup/>

### **Information We Collect Automatically**

This Site collects information automatically through the use of cookies, third party tracking technologies and server logs.  This information does not include any personal information.  We use this information primarily to monitor the use of this Site and to make improvements.  We may share this data with partners in order to enhance the functionality of this Site. 

**Cookies**

“Cookies” are small text files used to collect information about website activity.  No personal information is collected through our use of cookies.  This Site uses cookies for two main purposes: (a) to carry information about your current session at this Site from one web page to the next, which also allows you to automatically login to other Saginaw Valley State University websites, and (b) to identify you on this Site on return visits. 

You have the option of disabling or not accepting cookies by changing the preferences on your browser.  If you opt to disable cookies, you will still be able to use certain sections of our Site. However, you will not be able to use any parts of this Site that requires a login (e.g. accessing secured content, posting to message boards, etc).

**Third Party Tracking Technology**

The University’s websites uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). We also use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, part of a larger category of features known as Google Analytics Advertising Reporting Features. Google Analytics uses cookies (described above) to help the websites analyze how users use the sites. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the websites (including possibly your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google.  Site usage data collected through Google Analytics is not shared with other Google products and tools.  Our use of Google Analytics is in compliance with Google’s Terms of Service and the [SVSU’s Records Policy](http://www.svsu.edu/officeoftheregistrar/recordspolicy/).  Google provides [more information about Google’s privacy practices and information on how to opt-out of Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) tracking of your web browsing. 

**Advertising**

The University uses this information for Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, or Google Analytics Advertising Reporting Features. The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the university websites.

The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies to display content specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited university websites when those visitors go to other websites.

The university and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to report how visitor ad impressions, other uses of ad services and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to university websites.

The university uses data from Google’s interest-based advertising or third-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics to report, optimize and deliver interest-based advertisements.

## **Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

For security purposes and to ensure that the website remains available to all visitors, the University uses software to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage.

The University collects non-personal information about your Internet connection on this website, including but not limited to:

  * the Internet Protocol (IP) and the name of the Internet domain you used to access the Internet
  * the IP address or URL of the website from which you directly linked to this website
  * the date and time you accessed this website
  * the pages visited on this website
  * the browser and operating system you used to access this website
  * the search terms used on our search engines

The University uses this non-personal information to help manage the website and improve service.

## **Links**

This Site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we do not control or claim any responsibility for the privacy practices or content of such other sites. We encourage users to read the privacy statements of each website they visit.

## **Choice/Opt-out**

Our users are given the opportunity to receive communications from us.  However, at this time this Site does not manage or send communications.

## **Changes to Privacy Statement**

If we make changes to our privacy statement, we will indicate this on our home page. 

## **Disclaimer**

Neither Saginaw Valley State University nor any of its offices, programs, employees, agents or individual trustees, shall be liable for any improper or incorrect use of information obtained through the use of this Site.

## **Consent**

By using this Site you consent to the terms of this privacy statement.

## **Questions and feedback**

Your questions, comments and concerns are always welcome.  Please send us your feedback regarding the privacy statement or any other issues at [webcomm@svsu.edu](http://msu.edu/contactus.html).
